# Jason O'Dell

Chapel Hill, NC jasoneodell@gmail.com (336) 403-7837 Portfolio

# **Summary**

Full-stack developer with six years of experience in both web and mobile development. In my recent positions I have been a frontend developer as well as the lead developer and product owner for both the clinician web portal (Django) and its cross platform mobile app (Flutter). While working with a smaller team at startups, I have enjoyed the responsibility and autonomy of owning several products, developing and implementing many features, and learning many new technologies while working across the entire stack. I am excited to find a new role in which I can continue to learn and adapt my skillset and technical experience.

# **Work Experience**

Metapages Dec 2024 - Present

Frontend Developer

- Implemented redesign of the platform
- Updated the sidebar search and added a search modal utilizing Typesense
- Added a Stripe integration on the pricing page
- Created a versioning system allowing users to save versions and restore previous ones
- Added a groups and sharing feature using backend permissions

**VitalFlo** Oct 2020 - Oct 2024

Full-Stack Developer & Product Owner

- Product owner and lead developer on clinician portal
  - Built frontend for clinician web portal nearly from scratch (Django)
  - Designed and implemented 20+ new features including real time alerts, insurance billing tools, patient health trends, clinician decision support guides, automated patient health record reports, etc.
  - Reduced page load time by 65% by rebuilding our patients page using HTMX
  - Took over as Product Owner of mobile app
    - Learned Flutter to assume Product Ownership
    - Designed and implemented 5+ new features including patient health trends, new clinical testing (BRT), 3<sup>rd</sup>-party device integrations (spirometers, Awair), etc.
  - Integrated platform with Electronic Health Record (EHR) services for client
    - Created new UI/UX design and implementation in mobile apps
    - Collaborated with 3<sup>rd</sup>-party team (NextGen) to implement secure API integrations
    - Designed and implemented data pull workflows that mapped to clinician in-office experience and requirements
  - Directly Responsible Individual for all Product Requirements Documents, which are produced in close collaboration with Product Team for all feature development
  - Reviewed and provided feedback for 100+ pull requests for team members

## Freelance Developer

Sept 2019 - Present

Boone UAS Drones (https://www.booneuasdrones.com)

- Built business portfolio website for drone services business using React and Next.js Brianna Haferman Photography (https://www.briannahaferman.com)
  - Built creative media portfolio website using React and Next.js

Piedmont Legacy Trails (https://plt-blueways-map.vercel.app/)

- Built interactive river access points map in NC using HTML/CSS/Javascript and MapBox WordPress Developer
  - Designed WordPress websites for holiday lights business and podiatry firm

#### **Ekren Construction LLC**

Dec 2017 - Aug 2018

Carpentry Apprentice

 Assisted in various carpentry projects such as deck-building, framing, structural repair, kitchen/bathroom remodeling, etc

## Signal Mountain Lodge

May 2017 - Oct 2017

Cook

- Prepped ingredients and worked as a line cook at Grand Teton National Park
- Hiked 250+ miles of beautiful mountain terrain

# **Personal Projects**

# Wedding App

 My wife and I wanted to have an app for our wedding so I built one using Flutter which included an interactive Bingo game, quiz about us, itinerary, and more

#### **Spotify New Releases**

 Before Spotify had the "What's New" feature, I wanted to see all new releases from my followed artists so I built a web app to login via OAuth and display your new releases

#### Codebreaker

• I wanted to play around with the OpenAl API and we play the board game Codenames often so I built a Flutter app to screenshot the game board, send your words to OpenAl, then request the best ways to link the words together for clues

# Technical Skills, Languages, & Systems

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Javascript, React, Dart, Flutter
- Backend: Python, Django, Node.js, PostgreSQL
- CI/CD: AWS, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jenkins
- Tools: WordPress, Webflow, Figma, Adobe XD, Mapbox

## **Education**

#### **NC State University**

- Computer Programming Certificate, 2019-2020
- Bachelor of Science, Human Biology, 2011-2015